<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<feature id="org.nightlabs.vestigo.log4j.ui.feature" label="Vestigo log4j integration" provider-name="NightLabs Consulting GmbH" version="1.0.2.qualifier">

<!--
###PROPERTIES_BEGIN###
description.url = http://vestigo.nightlabs.com/${project.version}
description.text = Log4j integration for Vestigo.\n\nSee ${description.url} for more information.
###PROPERTIES_END###
-->

<!-- BEGIN: DO NOT MODIFY manually! The following is managed and your manual changes will be lost! -->
   <description url="http://vestigo.nightlabs.com/1.0.2-SNAPSHOT">Log4j integration for Vestigo.

See http://vestigo.nightlabs.com/1.0.2-SNAPSHOT for more information.</description>

   <copyright url="http://vestigo.nightlabs.com/1.0.2-SNAPSHOT/about/imprint.html">Copyright © 2011-2012 NightLabs Consulting GmbH. All rights reserved.</copyright>

   <license url="http://vestigo.nightlabs.com/1.0.2-SNAPSHOT/about/licence.html">License agreement for Vestigo


IMPORTANT! READ CAREFULLY: THIS IS A LEGAL AGREEMENT. BY DOWNLOADING,
INSTALLING, COPYING, SAVING ON YOUR COMPUTER, OR OTHERWISE USING THIS
SOFTWARE, YOU (LICENSEE, AS DEFINED BELOW) ARE BECOMING A PARTY TO
THIS AGREEMENT AND YOU ARE CONSENTING TO BE BOUND BY ALL THE TERMS
AND CONDITIONS OF THIS AGREEMENT.


1. Parties

(a) "LICENSOR" means NightLabs Consulting GmbH, having its principal
place of business at Weiherhofstr. 16, 79104 Freiburg, Germany,
registered with the Commercial Register kept by the Municipal Court of
Freiburg, HRB 7342.

(b) "LICENSEE" means the individual or legal entity downloading,
copying, installing, saving on his computer or otherwise using the
SOFTWARE (as defined below). For legal entities, LICENSEE includes any
entity which controls, is controlled by, or is under common control
with LICENSEE. For purposes of this definition, "control" means (i)
the power, direct or indirect, to cause the direction or management of
such entity, whether by contract or otherwise, or (ii) ownership of
fifty percent (50%) or more of the outstanding shares or beneficial
ownership of such entity.


2. Definitions

(a) "AUTHORIZED USER" means 
(i) if LICENSEE is an individual, solely LICENSEE; 
(ii) if LICENSEE is a legal entity, any employee, independent
contractor and other temporary worker authorized by LICENSEE to use
the SOFTWARE while performing duties within the scope of their
employment or assignment.

(b) "SOFTWARE" means the software program known as 'Vestigo - JDO/JPA
Query Browser' in binary form, including its documentation, upgrades
provided pursuant to Section 8 of this Agreement, and any third-party
software programs that are owned and licensed pursuant to Section 6 of
this Agreement by parties other than LICENSOR and that are either
integrated with or made part of Vestigo (collectively, "THIRD-PARTY
SOFTWARE").

(c) "FULL LICENSE" is a license purchased by the LICENSEE from the
LICENSOR. The FULL LICENSE is only valid, if the name of the LICENSEE
matches the data encoded in the LICENSE KEY (see below) (or shown on
the LICENSE ORDER CONFIRMATION (see below)) and the number of
individual users does not exceed the purchased number of AUTHORIZED
USERs.

(d) "EVALUATION LICENSE" is a license granted for the purpose of
evaluating the SOFTWARE. The EVALUATION LICENSE is automatically
granted by the LICENSOR to everyone downloading, copying, installing,
saving on his computer or otherwise using the SOFTWARE and not
possessing a valid FULL LICENSE.

(e) "LICENSE ORDER CONFIRMATION" means evidence of a FULL LICENSE
provided by LICENSOR to LICENSEE in electronic or printed form.

(f) "LICENSE KEY" means a unique key-code that enables AUTHORIZED
USER to use the SOFTWARE at a time. Only LICENSOR and/or its
representatives are permitted to produce LICENSE KEYs for the
SOFTWARE. A LICENSE KEY may expire. In this case, LICENSOR will
provide a new LICENSE KEY free of charge, if the FULL LICENSE
represented by the original LICENSE KEY is still valid.

(g) "CLIENT" means a computer device used by AUTHORIZED USER for
running the SOFTWARE.


3. Ownership

(a) The SOFTWARE is the property of LICENSOR or its suppliers. The
SOFTWARE is licensed, not sold. Title and copyrights to the SOFTWARE,
in whole and in part and all copies thereof, and all modifications,
enhancements, derivatives and other alterations of the SOFTWARE
regardless of who made any modifications, if any, are and will remain,
the sole and exclusive property of LICENSOR and its suppliers.

(b) The SOFTWARE is protected by German Copyright Law and Inter-
national Treaty provisions. Further, the structure, organization, and
code embodied in the SOFTWARE are the valuable and confidential trade
secrets of LICENSOR and its suppliers and are protected by
intellectual property laws and treaties. LICENSEE agrees to abide by
the copyright law and all other applicable laws of Germany including,
but not limited to, export control laws.


4. Grant of license

Subject to the terms, conditions, and limitations set forth in this
Agreement, including any amendments thereto, LICENSOR hereby grants to
LICENSEE a limited, non-exclusive, non-transferable license to use the
SOFTWARE as follows:

(a) LICENSEE may:

(i) install and use the SOFTWARE in the version range that has been
specified in the LICENSE ORDER CONFIRMATION on multiple CLIENTs and
operating systems, provided that a number of individual users never
exceeds the number of AUTHORIZED USERs specified in the LICENSE ORDER
CONFIRMATION;

(b) LICENSEE may not:

(i) sell, redistribute, encumber, give, lend, rent, lease, sublicense,
or otherwise transfer the SOFTWARE, or any portions of the SOFTWARE,
to anyone without the prior written consent of LICENSOR;

(ii) reverse engineer, decompile, disassemble, modify, translate, make
any attempt to discover the source code of the SOFTWARE, or create
derivative works from the SOFTWARE;

(iii) allow the use of the same LICENSE KEY to more individual users
than specified in the LICENSE ORDER CONFIRMATION. The SOFTWARE may
contain a feature preventing concurrent use of the same LICENSE KEY by
more AUTHORIZED USERs than specified in the LICENSE ORDER
CONFIRMATION.


5. THIRD-PARTY SOFTWARE license

(a) LICENSEE agrees to comply with the terms and conditions contained
in THIRD-PARTY SOFTWARE license agreements with respect to the
applicable THIRD-PARTY SOFTWARE.

(b) LICENSEE agrees and acknowledges that Sections 10 and 11 of this
Agreement shall also govern LICENSEE's use of the THIRD-PARTY
SOFTWARE. LICENSOR will have no responsibility with respect to any
THIRD-PARTY SOFTWARE, and LICENSEE will look solely to the LICENSOR(s)
of the THIRD-PARTY SOFTWARE for any remedy. LICENSOR claims no right
in the THIRD-PARTY SOFTWARE, and the same is owned exclusively by the
licensor(s) of the THIRD-PARTY SOFTWARE.

(c) LICENSOR provides no warranty, expressed or implied, including but
not limited to the implied warranties of merchantability or fitness
for a particular purpose, title, and non-infringement, with respect to
any THIRD-PARTY SOFTWARE.


6. Restricted use of the SOFTWARE under the EVALUATION LICENSE

(a) Subject to the terms of this Agreement, LICENSEE is granted a
right to use copies of SOFTWARE under the EVALUATION LICENSE for
evaluation purposes without charge.

(b) LICENSEE's use of evaluation-licensed copies shall be limited to
the internal evaluation of the SOFTWARE for the sole purpose of
determining whether the SOFTWARE meets LICENSEE's requirements and
whether LICENSEE desires to continue the use of the SOFTWARE.

(c) The SOFTWARE contains a feature that restricts the use of copies
not under FULL LICENSE. LICENSEE may not disable, destroy, or remove
this feature of the SOFTWARE, and any attempt to do so will be in
violation of this Agreement and will terminate LICENSEE's rights to
use the SOFTWARE.


7. License fees and payments

LICENSEE will pay to LICENSOR or a payment service provider appointed
by LICENSOR the license fee and other charges and expenses as set
forth in an appropriate invoice or other purchase documentation.
LICENSOR may charge LICENSEE interest for any payment that is more
than thirty (30) days past due at the rate of one and one-half percent
(1.5%) per month or the highest amount allowed by law, whichever is
lower.


8. Upgrades

(a) LICENSOR will provide generally available new versions of the
SOFTWARE to LICENSEE as follows:

(b) With the purchase of a FULL LICENSE for the SOFTWARE, LICENSEE
qualifies for free upgrades of the SOFTWARE within the version range
specified in the LICENSE ORDER CONFIRMATION (as well as in the
LICENCE KEY).


9. Limited warranty

The SOFTWARE is provided to LICENSEE "as is" and without warranties.
LICENSOR makes no warranty as to its use or performance. To the
maximum extent permitted by applicable law, LICENSOR, and its
affiliates, suppliers and resellers, disclaim all other warranties and
conditions, either expressed or implied, including, but not limited
to, implied warranties of merchantability, fitness for a particular
purpose, title, and non-infringement, with regard to the SOFTWARE, and
the provision of or failure to provide support services.


10. Disclaimer of damages

(a) To the maximum extend permitted by applicable law, in no event
will LICENSOR or its affiliates, LICENSORs, suppliers or resellers be
liable to LICENSEE under any theory for any damages suffered by
LICENSEE or any user of the SOFTWARE, or for any special, incidental,
indirect, consequential, or similar damages (including, but not
limited to, damages for loss of profits or confidential or other
information, for business interrruption, or personal injury, for loss
of privacy, for failure to meet any duty including of good faith or of
reasonable care, for negligence, and for any other pecuniary or other
loss whatsoever) arising out of the use or inability to use the
SOFTWARE, or the provision of or failure to provide support services,
even if LICENSOR has been advised of the possibility of such damages,
and regardless of the legal or equitable theory (contract, tort or
otherwise) upon which the claim is based.

(b) In any case, LICENSOR's entire liability under any provision of
this agreement will be limited to the amount actually paid by LICENSEE
for the SOFTWARE under this agreement.


11. Export regulations

LICENSEE agrees and accepts that the SOFTWARE may be subject to import
and export laws of any country, including those of the European Union
and the United States (specifically the Export Administration
Regulations (EAR)). LICENSEE acknowledges that it is not a restricted
end-user as defined by applicable export control laws. Further,
LICENSEE acknowledges that it will not download or otherwise export or
re-export the SOFTWARE or any related technical data directly or
indirectly to any restricted end-user or for any restricted end-use.


12. Term and termination

(a) Except as otherwise provided in LICENSE ORDER CONFIRMATION, the
license granted herein shall be perpetual.

(b) If LICENSEE fails to comply with the terms and conditions of this
Agreement, this Agreement and LICENSEE's right and license to use the
SOFTWARE will terminate immediately. LICENSEE may terminate this
Agreement at any time by notifying LICENSOR. Upon the termination of
this Agreement, LICENSEE must delete the SOFTWARE from its computers
and archives.

(c) LICENSEE agrees that upon termination of this agreement for any
reason, LICENSOR may take actions so that the SOFTWARE no longer
operates.


13. Marketing

LICENSEE agrees to be identified as a customer of LICENSOR and that
LICENSOR may refer to LICENSEE by name, trade name and trademark, if
applicable, and may briefly describe LICENSEE's business in LICENSOR's
marketing materials, on LICENSOR's web site, in public or legal
documents. LICENSEE hereby grants LICENSOR a license to use LICENSEE's
name and any of LICENSEE's trade names and trademarks solely pursuant
to this marketing section.


14. General

(a) LICENSOR reserves the right at any time to cease the support of
the SOFTWARE and to alter prices, features, specifications,
capabilities, functions, licensing terms, release dates, general
availability or other characteristics of the SOFTWARE.

(b) This Agreement, including the THIRD-PARTY SOFTWARE license
agreements, constitutes the entire agreement between the parties
concerning LICENSEE's use of the SOFTWARE, and supersedes any and all
prior or contemporaneous oral or written representations,
communications, or advertising with respect to the SOFTWARE. No
purchase order, other ordering document or any hand-written or
type-written text which purports to modify or supplement the printed
text of this Agreement or any schedule will add to or vary the terms
of this Agreement unless signed by both LICENSEE and LICENSOR.

(c) A waiver by either party of any term or condition of this
Agreement or any breach thereof, in any one instance, will not waive
such term or condition or any subsequent breach. The provisions of
this Agreement which require or contemplate performance after the
expiration or termination of this Agreement will be enforceable
notwithstanding said expiration or termination.

(d) This Agreement will be governed by the laws of Germany, without
reference to conflict of laws principles. LICENSEE agrees that any
litigation relating to this Agreement may only be brought in, and will
be subject to the jurisdiction of, any Court of Germany.

(e) Titles are inserted for convenience only and will not affect in
any way the meaning or interpretation of this Agreement. If any
provision of this Agreement is held invalid, the remainder of this
Agreement will continue in full force and effect. Either LICENSOR or
LICENSEE may assign this Agreement in the case of a merger or sale of
substantially all of its respective assets to another entity. This
Agreement will be binding upon and will inure to the benefit of the
parties, their successors and assigns.


For exceptions or modifications to this Agreement, please contact
LICENSOR at:
Address: Weiherhofstr. 16, 79104 Freiburg, Germany
E-mail: vestigo[at]nightlabs[dot]com
</license>
<!-- END: DO NOT MODIFY manually! The above is managed and your manual changes will be lost! -->

   <requires>
      <import feature="org.nightlabs.vestigo.ui.feature" match="greaterOrEqual" version="1.0.2"/>
   </requires>

   <plugin download-size="0" id="org.nightlabs.vestigo.log4j.core" install-size="0" unpack="false" version="0.0.0"/>

   <plugin download-size="0" id="org.nightlabs.vestigo.log4j.ui" install-size="0" unpack="false" version="0.0.0"/>

<!-- Necessary here AND in ${workspace}/org.nightlabs.vestigo.log4j.core/pom.xml -->
   <plugin download-size="0" id="slf4j.log4j12" install-size="0" unpack="false" version="0.0.0"/>
</feature>
