<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>                                                                                                             
<!--

    Vestigo - The JDO/JPA Query Tool And Browser - http://vestigo.nightlabs.com
    Copyright © 2011-2012 NightLabs Consulting GmbH. All rights reserved.

    This program and all its libraries in the namespace "*.nightlabs.vestigo.*"
    are proprietary software. Their source codes are trade secrets and therefore
    must be kept confidential.

    The use of this software is subject to licence terms.

    Please see LICENCE.txt or
    http://vestigo.nightlabs.com/latest-stable/about/licence.html for
    more details.

    For further information, please contact NightLabs Consulting GmbH:
    http://nightlabs.com

-->
<cheatsheet title="Create a Vestigo connection profile and query">                                                                                          
   <intro>                                                                                                                                         
      <description>
      	This cheat sheet shows you how to create a JPA connection profile and how to create and execute a simple JPA query<br/>                                                              
      </description>                                                                                                                               
   </intro>                                                                                                                                        
   <item title="Open the Vestigo perspective" dialog="true" skip="false">                                                                               
      <description>                                                                                                                                
         If the perspective is not already open open the perspective. 
         Select in the main menu <b>Window &gt; Show Perspective &gt; Other... &gt; Vestigo</b> or click on the link below.
      </description>
      <command
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.perspectives.showPerspective(org.eclipse.ui.perspectives.showPerspective.perspectiveId=org.nightlabs.vestigo.ui.VestigoPerspective)"/>                                                                                                                               
   </item>
   <item
         title="Download demo project">
      <description>
         You can download a demo project with simple JDO and JPA data-models. Open the browser 
         to download the demo project. to quickly get started using Vestigo. 
         The demo project is provided as zip file whose contents should be extracted to some directory
         on your hard drive you can easily relocate.
         <br/><br/> 
         The location of the demo project is: <b>http://vestigo.nightlabs.com/${project.version}/download/demo/org.nightlabs.vestigo.demo-${project.version}-bin.zip</b>
         <br/><br/> 
         The next step will open the Eclipse internal browser to download the zip. 
         The following will close the browser. You can of course skip these steps and download the file using an other method.
      </description>
      <subitem
            label="Open the browser to download the demo project."
            skip="true">
      	<command
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.browser.openBrowser(url=http://vestigo.nightlabs.com/${project.version}/download/demo/org.nightlabs.vestigo.demo-${project.version}-bin.zip)"/>
      </subitem>
      <subitem
            label="Close the browser that was used to download the demo project."
            skip="true">
      	<command
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.file.close"/>
      </subitem>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Start the Connection Profile Wizard"
         dialog="true">
      <description>
         Select the <b>Data Source Explorer</b> view and right-click on the <b>JPA Connections</b> entry in the tree of connection types. 
         Invoke the <b>New...</b> action from the context menu.
      </description>
      <action
      		class="org.nightlabs.vestigo.ui.cheatsheet.action.OpenConnectionProfileWizardAction"
      		pluginId="org.nightlabs.vestigo.ui"
      	/>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Define a connection name">
      <description>
      	 Enter a name for the connection. Use for example <b>Demo JPA connection</b>. 
      	 When finished click the <b>Next</b> button of the wizard.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Define the classpath for the connection">
      <description>
      	 In the next step you must define the classpath for the conneciton. 
      	 The classpath of your connection must include your datamodel, the JPA implementation and the JDBC drivers to access the database.
      	 For the demo project all is provided in the projects zip-file as separate jars.
      	 <br/><br/>
      	 Use the first action of the wizard page to <b>Add one or more files (EAR, JAR, WAR etc.).</b> In the dialog that opens browse to the
      	 directory you've extracted the demo project to and select <b>all jar-files</b>, then click <b>OK</b>. 
      	 <br/><br/>
      	 Note, that Vestigo also allows to add all contents of an archive (zip, war, ear etc.) or folder recursively. However for this  
      	 tutorial we will use the separate jars.
      	 <br/><br/>
      	 When you've added all jars of the demo project click the <b>Next</b> button.      
      </description>
   </item> 
   <item
         title="Choose the persistence unit">
      <description>
      	 When the <b>Persistence unit</b> page opens it automatically searches for persistence units in your classpath. 
      	 For the demo project it will find two persistence units, please use the one for JPA: <b>vestigoDemoMovieJPA</b>. 
      	 Select the persistence unit from the table and click <b>Next</b>.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Check and override persistence properties">
      <description>
         The next page will initially show you all properties from the persistence unit you have selected. 
      	 Note that these entries are displayed in light gray indicating that they are inherited from the persistence unit.
      	 For this demo you need to override one entry, the connection url defining the coordinates to the derby database 
      	 containing the demo data.
      	 <br/><br/> 
      	 Change the entry with the key <b>javax.persistence.jdbc.url</b> to match the path of the
      	 folder you've extracted the demo project to. For example on Linux the the new value might look like this 
      	 <b>jdbc:derby:/home/myuser/tmp/vestigo-demo/derby/vestigoDemoMovieJPA</b>. 
      	 On Windows the Entry might look something like the following: 
      	 <b>jdbc:derby:C:\Users\myuser\Desktop\vestigo-demo\derby\vestigoDemoMovieJPA</b>
      	 <br/><br/>
      	 Note that after changing the value the entry will be automatically checked and displayed with a fat font indicating
      	 that you have overwritten the value from the persistence unit.
      	 <br/><br/>
      	 When you're done changing the value click the <b>Test Connection</b> button in order to check your settings. 
      	 If the ping succeeds you can <b>Finish</b> the dialog. You've just created your first Vestigo JPA connection profile. 
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Connect the profile">
      <description>
      	 After you've created the connection profile you can connect it. 
      	 Select the new connection in the <b>Data Source Explorer</b> view, right-click and select <b>Connect</b>.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Show the candidate classes">
      <description>
      	 After the connection has been established the <b>Candidate classes</b> view will load all classes that are possible
      	 candidates for a query. Bring the view to the foreground in order to see the list of candidate classes. 
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Create simple query for a candidate class">
      <description>
      	 In order to create a simple query selecting all instances of a class you only have to <b>double-click the class</b> in the 
      	 <b>Candidate classes</b> view. Choose the <b>org.nightlbs.vestigo.demo.jpa.Movie</b> class and double-click. 
      	 This will create a new query editor already including the select statement.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Execute the query">
      <description>
      	 To execute the query use the <b>Execute</b> Button ([Ctrl + F5]) or double-click once again on the
      	 In order to create a simple query selecting all instances of a class you only have to <b>double-click the class</b> in the 
      	 <b>Candidate classes</b> view. This will create a new query editor already including the select statement.
      	 <br/><br/>
      	 The query is executed and you can now browse the results in the <b>Result Sets</b> and <b>Object Graph Detail Tree</b> views. 
      </description>
   </item>
</cheatsheet>
